Gregory Strom

Full Stack Web Developer

Web developer redeploying exceptional communication and analytic skills honed as a University-level teacher of philosophy and logic into a programming career. Extensive international experience collaborating with students and colleagues to solve conceptual problems and make exciting ideas work.

PROJECTS

Meet App | https://gbstrom.github.io/meet/

 Serverless PWA hosted on Amazon Lambda that works with Google Calendar API and login handled by Google OAuth2. Built with HTML, CSS, JS, React

myFlix API & Angular client | https://gbstrom.github.io/myFlix-Angular-client/

Angular front-end client for back-end movie API built with JS, MongoDB

WORK EXPERIENCE

University of Pittsburgh, Department of Physics & Astronomy

Administrative Secretary, September 2019 – present | Pittsburgh

 Learned EverWeb independently to create, maintain and update the "Coffee House" website facilitating international collaboration between chemists and physicists on groundbreaking research publications

Math-M-Addicts

Assistant Teacher, September 2020 – present | New York

 Mastered advanced math concepts to teach in weekly online courses for children ages 10-12, with autonomy and responsibility gradually increasing to include multiple courses and independent teaching

University of Pittsburgh, Department of Philosophy

Visiting Lecturer/Instructor, August 2013 – May 2021 | Pittsburgh

- Reinstated and organized annual Visitors' Conference, permanently enriching Department culture by establishing international professional relationships between philosophers in 6 universities
- Enhanced Department's teaching capability by adventurously expanding teaching repertoire to include 9 new subjects, crafting syllabuses and delivering lectures for 27 undergraduate and 17 adult education courses
- Supervised and evaluated teams of 2-4 teaching assistants

Website Manager, January 2011 – August 2011 | Pittsburgh

 Taught myself HTML and CSS to maintain and update faculty supervisor's academic website, augmenting availability of his research to colleagues

Carnegie Mellon University, Department of Philosophy

Special Faculty, August 2019 – December 2020 | Pittsburgh

 Created syllabuses and delivered lectures for 4 undergraduate courses, with increasing autonomy in course design

University of Sydney, Centre for Time

Postdoctoral Fellow, July 2011 – July 2013 | Sydney, Australia

• Coordinated weekly international guest speaker program while supervising graduate level dissertation project and instructing 2 graduate seminars

gbstrom@gmail.com +1-412-759-4591 Pittsburgh, PA, USA github.com/gbstrom linkedin.com/in/gbstrom gbstrom.github.io/portfolio/

SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Node
- React
- React Native
- React Bootstrap
- Angular
- Angular Material
- Git
- Responsive Design
- jQuery
- Test Driven Development
- Configuring Heroku
- AWS
- MongoDB

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

CareerFoundry - online May 2021 – March 2022

PhD in Philosophy

University of Pittsburgh August 2003 – August 2011

BA in Philosophy

University of Chicago September 1998 – June 2002

RESEARCH

'Deviant Causal Chains, Knowledge of Reasons, and *Akrasia*'

Published in *Topoi*, April 2014

'Multitasking, Consequentialism and Practical Imagination'

PhD Thesis University of Pittsburgh, 2011